Guru Ashtakam (Sanskrit 15) (Shri Adi Shankaracharya - Eight Stanzas in Praise of the Guru)
Guru Ashtakam (Sanskrit 15) (Shri Adi Shankaracharya - Otto strofe in lode del Guru)
Shareeram Suroopam Sada Roga Muktam "Though your body be comely and ever remain in perfect health"
Shareeram Suroopam Sada Roga Muktam "Seppure il tuo corpo sia avvenente e sempre in perfetta salute"
Yashashcharu Chitram Dhanam Meru Tulyam "Though your name be unsullied, and mountain-high your hoarded gold"
Yashashcharu Chitram Dhanam Meru Tulyam "Seppure il tuo nome sia immacolato e tu abbia accumulato montagne d’oro"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Kalatram Dhanam Putra Pautra Adi Sarvam "Even if fortune blesses you with riches and a virtuous wife"
Kalatram Dhanam Putra Pautra Adi Sarvam "Seppure la fortuna ti benedica con ricchezze ed una moglie virtuosa,"
Kalatram Dhanam Putra Pautra Adi Sarvam "Even if fortune blesses you with riches and a virtuous wife"
Kalatram Dhanam Putra Pautra Adi Sarvam "Seppure la fortuna ti benedica con ricchezze ed una moglie virtuosa"
Gruham Bandhawah Sarvam Etaddhi Jatam "With children and their children, with friendship and the joys of home"
Gruham Bandhawah Sarvam Etaddhi Jatam "Con figli e figli dei figli, amicizie e gioie domestiche
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Shadangadi Vedo Mukhe Shastra Vidya "Though the lore of the Vedas take up its dwelling on your tongue"
Shadangadi Vedo Mukhe Shastra Vidya "Seppure la scienza dei Veda prenda dimora sulla tua lingua"
Kavitvadi Gadyam Supadyam Karoti "Though you be learned in scripture, gifted in writing prose and verse"
Kavitvadi Gadyam Supadyam Karoti "Seppure tu sia erudito nella scrittura, versato nei componimenti in prosa e poesia"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Videsheshu Manyah Swadesheshu Dhanyah "Even if you be honoured at home and famed in foreign lands"
Videsheshu Manyah Swadesheshu Dhanyah "Seppure onorato in patria e famoso all’estero"
Sadachara Vruteshu Matto Na Chanyah "Given to pious deeds and ever averse to wickedness"
Sadachara Vruteshu Matto Na Chanyah "Dedito ad azioni religiose e sempre avverso alla malvagità"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Kshama Mandale Bhoopa Bhoopala Vrundaih "Though you become, at last, the emperor of the universe"
Kshama Mandale Bhoopa Bhoopala Vrundaih "Seppure tu divenissi infine l’imperatore dell’universo"
Kshama Mandale Bhoopa Bhoopala Vrundaih "Though you become, at last, the emperor of the universe"
Kshama Mandale Bhoopa Bhoopala Vrundaih "Seppure tu divenissi infine l’imperatore dell’universo"
Sada Sevitam Yasya Padara Vindam "Though you possess for servants the mightiest of kings of the earth"
Sada Sevitam Yasya Padara Vindam "E avessi come servitori i re più potenti della terra"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Yashash Ched Gatam Dikshu Dana Pratapat "Even if every nation resounds with your beneficence"
Yashash Ched Gatam Dikshu Dana Pratapat "Seppure ogni nazione risuonasse della tua beneficienza"
Jagatvastu Sarvam Kare Yat Prasadat "By His (of the Guru) grace everything is won in this world"
Jagatvastu Sarvam Kare Yat Prasadat "Per la Sua (del Guru) grazia viene ottenuta ogni cosa in questo mondo"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Na Bhoge Na Yoghe Na Va Vaji Medhe "Though you pursue no pleasures, derive no happiness from wealth or spouse"
Na Bhoge Na Yoghe Na Va Vaji Medhe "Seppure tu non insegua piaceri, non tragga felicità da ricchezze o consorte"
Na Bhoge Na Yoghe Na Va Vaji Medhe "Though you pursue no pleasures, derive no happiness from wealth or spouse"
Na Bhoge Na Yoghe Na Va Vaji Medhe "Seppure tu non insegua piaceri, non tragga felicità da ricchezze o consorte"
Na Kanta Sukhe Naiva Vittheshu Chittam "Reject the powers of yoga, and scorn the fruits of sacrifice"
Na Kanta Sukhe Naiva Vittheshu Chittam "Rifiuti i poteri dello Yoga e disdegni i frutti del sacrificio"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Aranye Na Na Swasya Gehe Na Karye "Even if you are ready to dwell in the forest as at home"
Aranye Na Na Swasya Gehe Na Karye "Seppure sia pronto a dimorare nella foresta come nella tua casa"
Na Dehe Mano Vartate Me Twanardhye "No more attached to work, unstrained by the body"
Na Dehe Mano Vartate Me Twanardhye "Non più attaccato al lavoro, non costretto dal corpo"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji
Gurorashtakam Yah Pathet Punya Dehi "That noble soul who ponders these verses in the Guru's praise"
Gurorashtakam Yah Pathet Punya Dehi "La nobile anima che medita su questi versi in lode del Guru"
Gurorashtakam Yah Pathet Punya Dehi "That noble soul who ponders these verses in the Guru's praise"
Gurorashtakam Yah Pathet Punya Dehi "La nobile anima che medita su questi versi in lode del Guru"
Yatir Bhoopatir Brahmachari Cha Gehi "Of all ascetics and students, of all rulers and worldly men"
Yatir Bhoopatir Brahmachari Cha Gehi "Fra tutti gli asceti e studiosi, fra tutti i governanti e uomini di questo mondo"
Labhhed Vanchhitartham Padam Brahma Sangyam "Will attain tha Brahman, the treasure coveted by all"
Labhhed Vanchhitartham Padam Brahma Sangyam "Conseguirà il Brahman, il tesoro da tutti anelato"
Gurorukta Vakye Mano Yasya Lagnam "By applying his mind with constant zeal to the Guru's teaching"
Gurorukta Vakye Mano Yasya Lagnam "Applicando la mente con costante zelo agli insegnamenti del Guru"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet"
Manashchenna Lagnam Guroranghri Padme "Se la mente non è assorbita ai Piedi di Loto del Guru"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "What will it all avail you? What indeed will it avail you?"
Tatah Kim Tatah Kim (x 2) "A cosa ti servirà tutto ciò? A cosa ti servirà?
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji Jay Mataji, Jay Mataji
Jay Mataji, Shri Mataji, Jay Mataji Jay Mataji, Jay Mataji